Guide to the Robert E. Simon, Jr. papers, 1960-2006
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 10: Oversize 1960-2006, (3 boxes)
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Her Job Is to Banish New-Town Blues", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    396.5
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "How Important Is a Tree?", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    396.6
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "New Reston Community To Be Subject of Study", "Study of Reston To Be Financed By Ford Grant", "Foundation Approves Grant for Study of Reston Project" and "New Cities Sprout Up As Population Zooms", 1963 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    396.7
  - Newsclipping: Northern Virginia Sun, "Reston Approved", "Reston 'Community Zone' Approved for Fairfax" and "Project Will House 75,000", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    396.8
  - Newsclipping: Richmond Times, "Developer Plans to Build Entire City in Fairfax" and The Washington Post "Area Planners Face Challenge", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    396.9
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Planners Back Zoning For 'Reston Concept'", The Washington Post, "Unit Backs Reston Ordinance" and Daily News, "Reston Goes Trail-Blazing", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    396.10
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Satellite Town" and "Reston Development Depends on Zoning" and The Washington Post, "Planned City", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    396.11
  - Newsclipping: The Herndon-Chantilly Times, "Planning Commission Expected to Approve Reston Development", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    396.12
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "Reston Community Decision May Alter Suburban Growth" and "Reston To Be Complete Community", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    396.13
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Fairfax Supervisors Consider Third Sunset Hills Proposal", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    396.14
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Fairfax Reaction Mixed on Plan for Reston", The Washington Post, "Cluster Plan Proposed to Cut Fairfax Sprawl" and "New Concept Proposed for Sunset Hills" and The Washington Daily News, "Reston ASks New Rules", 1962 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    396.15
  - Newsclipping: Fairfax County Sun Echo, "Sunset Hills' New Owner Announces Plans", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    396.16
  - Newsclipping: Fairfax County Sun Echo, "Board Hears 'Reston' Plans", 1961 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    396.17
  - Scrapbook of Original Newsclippings, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    397.1
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "Weaver Says Action, Hard Work Needed", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    397.2
  - The New Town Diagram, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    397.3
  - The New Town Floor Plan, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    397.4
  - Town Center Diagram, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    397.5
  - Newsclippings: Alexandria Gazette, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    397.6
  - Newsclippings: The Wall Street Journal, "Building Cities", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    397.7
  - Newsclippings: "Building Pace Changes Face of Broad Area", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    397.8
  - Newsclipping: Northern Virginia Sun, "Allmen Slates Fairfax Project" and "Hazelton Lab Branch Is Located in Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    397.9
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "Junior Hunt Horse Show SEt July 24", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    397.10
  - Newsclipping: Times Pirayune, "New Concepts Lead to Better Planning", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    397.11
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Daily News, "D.C. Could Be the Capital of Tennis World", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    397.12
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "Vespers Planned at Reston Lake", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    397.13
  - Newsclipping: "Utilities Going Into Air-Conditioning Business-It's Paying Off Cooly", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    397.14
  - Newsclipping: "High Density Housing and Rural Landscape Will Meet in the City Planned by R.E. Simon", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    397.15
  - Newsclipping: "Topping Out of Reston's Tallest", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    397.16
  - Newsclipping: "They're Building the City of the Future", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    397.17
  - Newsclipping: The Kansas City Star, "Cooling as New Utility Service", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    397.18
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "For and About Women", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    397.19
  - Newsclipping: "200 Entries Expected For Truro Horse Show", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    397.20
  - Newsclipping: "Nation's Cities", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    397.21
  - News Photos, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    397.22
  - Newsclipping: "City of Future Comes to Life", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Newsclipping: "Horse Show", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    397.24
  - Newsclipping: "New City Is Taking Shape", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    397.25
  - Newsclipping: "Reston Heavily Toured", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    397.26
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "You Can Move Into Your Reston Townhouse Before School Starts", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    397.27
  - Newsclipping: "Suppose You Could Drive Out Here This Weekend", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    397.28
  - Newsclipping: The Evening Star, "Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    397.29
  - Newsclipping: Richmond Times-Dispatch, "Reston: City for Country Lovers", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    397.30
  - Newsclipping:, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Newsclipping: "They're Off and Jumping in Fairfax", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    397.32
  - Newsclipping: "Mission Pulpit Suits His Needs", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 33)
    397.33
  - Newsclipping: "Virginia Homes of '66 Exhibited", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    397.34
  - Newsclipping: "Meet the Press", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    397.35
  - Newsclipping: "A Quick Look at Today's Housing Trends", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    397.36
  - Newsclipping: "Reston Takes Shape as a Town, And It Takes Much Money, Too", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    397.37
  - Newsclipping: "And Culture Too: Reston Creator Believes in More Than Accommodation", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    397.38
  - Newsclipping: "Developer of Reston Values County's Help", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    397.39
  - Newsclipping: "Carnegie Hall To Reston, Va.", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    397.40
  - Newsclipping: "Industry Is Given Major Role In Development of New Va. City", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    397.41
  - Newsclipping: "U.S. Chamber Studying What's Wrong With Cities", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    397.42
  - Newsclipping: The Reston Times, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    397.43
  - Newsclipping: "Red-Eyed, Green-Eyed Surveyors", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    397.44
  - Newsclipping: Reston Times, "Times Editorials", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    397.45
  - Newsclipping: "This Month In Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    397.46
  - Newsclipping: "The Vienna Trust Company is Coming to Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    397.47
  - Newsclipping: "This Month In Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    397.48
  - Newsclipping: "Next Year's Construction Plans-Lake Anne Village", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    397.49
  - Advertisements, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    397.50
  - Newsclipping: "The Appraiser", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    397.51
  - Newsclipping: The Washington Post, "Hancock to Have 21 Million Dollars Stake In Reston Town", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    397.52
  - Newsclipping: "That Reston Sure Turned the Tide", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    397.532
  - Newsclipping: "Industry Comes to Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    397.54
  - Thank You from Capital By Lines, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    397.55
  - Newsclipping: "Some Men Who Made Marks in '65", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 56)
    397.56
  - Newsclipping: "Still Hope for a Model Suburb in the City", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    397.57
  - Newsclipping: "BP's Aide Takes Tour of Reston", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    397.58
  - Newsclipping: "Underdeveloped: Strangling Debt", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 59)
    397.59
  - Newsclipping: "The Critical Eye", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 60)
    397.60
  - Newsclipping: "Robert E. Simon, Builder of the Washington Area's Most Advanced New Town, Talks About the Reston Experiment", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 61)
    397.62
  - Newsclipping: "Reston Counts 1000 Residents and Now Looks Like New Town", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Newsclipping: "Let's Face It A Monthly Commentary", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 63)
    397.63
  - Newsclipping: "Congressional Record", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 64)
    397.64
  - Newsclipping: "Geological Survey Unveils Plans for Big Reston Complex", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 65)
    397.65
  - Newsclipping: "International Flavor At Reston Ceremony", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    397.66
  - Newsclipping: "She Mothers New City", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    397.67
  - Newsclipping: "From the Desk of Christian C. Lunnow", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 68)
    397.68
  - Newsclipping: "James B. Selonick", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 69)
    397.69
  - Newsclipping: "Geological Survey Unveils Plans for Big Reston Complex", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 70)
    397.70
  - Newsclipping: The Wall Street Journal, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 71)
    397.71
  - Newsclipping: "Reston, Virginia-A New Town", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 72)
    397.72
  - Newsclipping: "Engineer", 1965 (Box 15, Folder 73)
    397.73
  - Newsclipping: "D.C. Firm Wins 2 AIA Awards", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 74)
    397.74
  - Newsclipping: "Mall Swings for Urban Conference Delegates, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 75)
    397.75
  - Newsclipping: "Reston", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 76)
    397.76
  - Newsclipping: "Instant Towns", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 77)
    397.77
  - Newsclipping: "Reston Time for an Afternoon Sail on the Lake", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 78)
    397.78
  - Newsclipping: New York Times, "Co-Op City", 1966 (Box 15, Folder 79)
    397.79
  - Newsclipping: The New York Times, "Reston To Study Low-Income Units", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 80)
    397.80
  - Newsclipping: "Reston Developer Bars Sameness", 1967 (Box 15, Folder 81)
    397.81
  - Reston: A Conception, 1962 (Volume 1)
    A large book with a dedication to Robert Simon from his wife. There are also early Reston area and building design plans on many of the pages.